Finding Aid for Richard A. Forsyth papers, ca. 1907-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Richard A. Forsyth papers ca. 1907-1970
Forsyth, Richard Alexander.
1 linear foot
85168 Aa 2
Student at the University of Michigan, later professional stage actor. Playbills from Detroit and University of Michigan productions, theatrical publications, miscellaneous correspondence, clippings, and writings; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was transferred from the library of Eastern Michigan University (donor no. 2018 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Richard A. Forsyth received his B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1920 and his law degree in 1922. While a student, Forsyth was a member of the Mimes and the Comedy Club. He also appeared in several Union Operas, including "Top O' The Morning." As a practicing attorney in Detroit, Forsyth was well known in amateur theater, both as actor and director, where he contributed to many stage successes. For several years he served as President of The Players.
The Forsyth collection includes some correspondence, journals (1914-1917), playbills from productions in the Detroit and Ann Arbor area, clippings about his theatrical career, and miscellaneous photographs.
Subjects:
Actors.; Forsyth, Richard Alexander.; Theater--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Theater--Michigan--Detroit.; University of Michigan--Dramatics.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Forsyth, Richard Alexander.; Theatrical productions.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Personal
  - Biographical and personal, ca. 1907-1934 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1948 (Box 1)
  - Journals
    - 1914-1916 (Box 1)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 1)
- Theatrical career and related
  - Player's Playhouse, Detroit, Mich.
    - General (scattered dates) (Box 1)
    - The Player magazine, 1926-1959, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Playbills, ca. 1926-1959, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Playbills (Detroit area)
    - Miscellaneous theatres, ca. 1930-1934 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1925-1961 (Box 1)
  - Playbills (local)
    - Ann Arbor Theatre, ca. 1938-1970 (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan
      - Department of Speech, 1942-1970 (Box 1)
      - Drama Season, 1959-1964 (Box 1)
      - Professional Theatre
        - 1962-1966 (Box 1)
        - 1967-1071 (Box 1)
      - University Musical Society
        - 1926-1928 (Box 1)
        - 1956-1970 (Box 1)
      - Theatres, miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Whitney Theatre, ca. 1925-1927 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Scripts
    - Undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - ca. 1924-1927 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Caribbean trip, 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous poems, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous and undated (Box 1)
    - ca. 1922-1928 (Box 1)
    - 1929-1931 (Box 1)
    - 1932-1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1952 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Photographs of theatrical productions; also portraits (Box 1)